Okay, there we go. Okay then, so welcome to Yoga with G. So I just want us to
take this
moment to just forget about whatever else is going on in our busy lives and let
's just
try to be in the present moment and we really just want to lose ourselves in
our breath and
in our practice today. So what is the goal of yoga? So yoga isn't about
achieving the
perfect pose or touching your toes or finding an instant calm, although that
will happen
inevitably. But the goal is more about stripping back layer by layer to meet
the deepest parts
of yourself and to reveal who you are beneath the noise. So to meet yourself on
a deeper
level and to realise what you want beyond the programming and beyond life's
pressures
and to realise that you are already whole and beneath it all there is peace. So
yoga
philosophy is about bringing harmony between your body, your spirit and your
mind and teachings
of yoga revolve around self awareness, spiritual knowledge and detachment and
enlightenment
of the mind. So yoga is more than just a physical practice, it's a way of life.
And
there are five main principles of yoga. Number one is the asana, which is a
physical practice.
Number two is parayama, which is breathing, so energy flow. Number three is sh
avasana,
which is proper relaxation, which we're going to do at the end of the practice.
Number four
is proper diet and nutrition and number five is positive thinking and
meditation. Okay,
so before we get started, I'll just talk briefly about breathing as this is a
big part of the
practice. So you want to try and breathe gently and slowly and breathe through
our nose in
the practice. So we can slow down our breathing and elongate our exhalation,
but without any
force or pressure. So we can get used to being conscious about our breath and
being a word
of the breath. And if you feel any pains or anything like that in the practice,
instead
of resorting to a shallow breath, just breathe into the pain and allow your
body to release
the tension as you breathe out. Of course, if you feel, you know, if the pain's
too much,
if you're in a position that really doesn't feel good, you can gently remove
yourself from
that posture, no problem. But you know, if it's just a little bit of tightness,
you can
breathe out and let the tightness go with the breath. Before we start, does
anyone have
any injuries I need to be aware of or anyone pregnant? Okay, all good. And
remember just
to go at your own pace and be kind to your body and don't force yourself into a
posture
that you're not ready for. This is your practice. I will show a couple of
variations for different
postures. So just choose whatever level feels best to you in your body. Let
your body choose
and not your ego. Okay, so I'm going to start with some sun salutations. So I
do these at
the start of all of my practices. And even if you only have five to 10 minutes
in the
morning, you can just do sun salutations. And that is enough if you don't have
time to
do a full practice. So I will show you what a sun salutation looks like first,
and then
we'll flow through them together. Actually, before we start that, I actually
want to
just bring this to a meditation first, just to get us into the present moment.
So let's
come to us comfortable seated position on our mat. So on the carpet, wherever
we are.
We can rest our palms on our knees like this, if our palms face them upwards.
This allows
any, anything that is meant for us to be received, we can close down our eyes
and just come to
the breath. So let's just take some nice deep breaths in and exhale. Just
continue with
a nice long, deep breath. While we're here, I would like to start an intention
for today's
practice. Maybe it's I intend to find inner peace and tranquility. Maybe it's I
intend
to be fully present in today's practice, or it could be to deepen your
flexibility and
range of motion. Whatever it is, just come to an intention now for your
practice today.
I'm going to end this with free deep breaths and as we exhale, we're going to
sigh it all
out. So in three, two, one, let's breathe in. And out. And again. One more.
Okay, we can open our eyes now. I will show you this on salutation and then we
can flow
through them together. Okay. So we're going to start at the front of our mats
in Mountain
Pose. So Mountain Pose is basically just standing with your legs hip width
apart, your arms
and palms facing forward. And you just want to bring awareness to your body and
just make
sure that you're nice and centered. So you're not slouching over to one side.
You're really
nice and centered. This is Mountain Pose. Now we're going to inhale as we
release our
arms above our head. And exhale as we bend forward. And inhale as we lift our
head above
our heart. And exhale as we come down, place our palms in the mat and walk our
feet back
and bring ourselves down. So I'll show you two variations. Come down like so or
you can
use your knees and bring yourself down like this. When we're here, we're going
to inhale
as we push back into upward facing dog. And then on the exhale, we're going to
push back
into downward dog. And then on the final inhale, we're going to walk our feet
forward to the
mat, front of the mat. Lift our head above our heart again, fold over, bend,
fold over
the leg up. So that is one stone salutation. So we're going to flow through
them together.
We're going to do about five to ten of those. So if we all want to come to the
front of
our mat and mountain pose, bring our shoulders away from our ears, open the
chest as we inhale,
stretch your arms above our head. And exhale, bend forward with a flat back,
keep your back
nice and straight and hinge up the hips. Inhale as you bend your head above
your heart. Exhale,
place your palms on your mat and walk your feet back. Now do whatever variation
you need
to get onto the ground. Inhale as you lift up into upward facing dog. And exh
ale as you
push back into downward facing dog. So while we're here, we can just pedal our
feet out,
take some nice breaths. And on the next inhale, just start to walk your feet to
the front
of the mat. Exhale as you fold all the way forward. Inhale, head above your
heart. Exhale,
fold forward. Inhale as we come back up, just bending. So how is that for
everyone? Is that
okay? You understand the flow? Yeah, perfect. Okay, so let's go through them
again. We can
do maybe five or so more of these and just flow with your own breath. Okay, let
's get into mountain
pose. Inhale, exhale, bend over, hinge up the hips, keeping your back nice and
straight.
Exhale, lift up. Exhale, bring your hands down and walk your feet back.
So perfect. Now exhale and down with facing dog.
Just pedal your feet out. Just feel a little bit lesser. And on your next inh
ale, we want to
walk our feet forward. Exhale, inhale if you're head above your heart. Exhale,
fold all the way
forward. Inhale, pull your stretch with your arms up and bring your hands down
into prayer position.
Perfect. Okay, let's do a few more of those. This time, we can set up walking
our feet back and
forward. We can hop them back and forward. It's up to you if you want to
continue to walk them,
or if you want to hop them back and forth. I'll show you what I mean. So on
this, we're here.
Instead of walking back, you can just jump back. And when we're working down
with dog here,
instead of walking forward, you can look up, bend your knees, and hop. So it's
up to you
what variation you want to do. Okay, so let's go to mountain pose at the front
of our mat. Inhale,
exhale, fold forward. Inhale, raise your head above your heart. Exhale, bring
your hands to the mat.
Jump back or walk back. Inhale, up with face and dog. Exhale, down with face
and dog.
Nice. Okay. Inhale, walk, or jump your feet forward. Exhale, bend over.
Inhale, lift your head above your heart. Exhale, fold forward. Inhale, come all
the way up.
Stretch up and hands in preposition. Nice. Okay, let's do a few more.
Inhale, lift, head up. Exhale, bring your palms down, feet to the back of the
mat.
Inhale, up with face and dog. Exhale, down with face and dog.
Take a breath here.
Move down with face and dog. You want to bring your shoulders away from your
ears.
Keep your back nice and straight. If your ankles aren't touching the floor,
that's absolutely fine.
You want to just focus on giving your back nice and straight and turn your
inside of your elbows
out, so the piece of your arm turn outwards. Okay, on the next inhale, we're
going to walk
or jump our feet to the front of the mat. Exhale, fold all the way over.
Inhale, lift your head above your heart. Exhale, fold forward.
Inhale, come all the way up, back to bed by back to break.
Okay, we'll do one more of those.
Onto mountain pose. Inhale. Exhale, fold forward.
Inhale, head above your heart.
Exhale, bring your feet to the back of the mat.
Inhale up with face and dog. Exhale, down with face and dog.
Take another breath here. Nice big deep inhale and even deeper exhale.
And on the next inhale, you want to walk your feet or jump your feet to the
front of the mat.
Exhale, fold all the way over.
Inhale, head above your heart.
And exhale, fold all the way over again.
And inhale, bring yourself back to standing.
Okay, nice.
Okay, so next we're just going to flow through that again, but when we're in
our downward dog,
we're going to go into a different posture, but I'll talk you through when we
're there.
So let's continue the same rhythm that we've just done.
Mountain pose.
We're going to inhale and exhale, fold forward.
Inhale, head above heart.
Exhale, bring your feet to the back of the mat.
Inhale, upward face and dog.
Exhale, push back into downward face and dog.
Okay, now that we are here, we are going to lift our right leg up into the air
for our three-legged dog.
And then we're going to bring it forward all the way up to our elbow,
pass it over and lower down into pigeon pose.
You girls see me here?
So I've got one leg up the front, which is in a 90-degree angle.
Well, it's not quite 90-degree, actually, it's probably less than a 90-degree
angle.
Then our back leg, just check that it's nice and straight and aligned.
This is a really nice stretch for your hips, your legs, your groin.
So let's take some nice deep breaths here.
If it's in your practice today, you can walk your hands forward and lower
yourself
onto your front leg and just rest your third eye on your mat.
Exhale, nice deep breath.
And then you can bring yourself back up.
I just like to do a lot of bend here as well.
We've folded forward to just bend yourself back slightly.
Nice. Now what we're going to do is we're going to bring our left leg all the
way around
to the front and then cross it over your right leg.
Nice twisty one.
So you want both your bum cheeks to be on the floor.
Then we're going to take our right hand, bring it over and just place the elbow
just on top of the left knee, yep.
And then our left hand is going to come behind and our gaze is going to look
over our left shoulder.
This is a really good detoxifying posture.
So if you ever feel like you're backed up when you need to go to the toilet,
you can do this posture and it really helps as it's twisting your bowels.
So let's take some deep breaths here.
Nice.
Now let's release and we're just going to take ourselves over to the other side
.
Just going to count to twist, just a quick count to twist.
So we're just going to bring our left arm over to our left leg and just twist
out to the other side.
Just very quick count to twist.
Okay, nice.
Now let's release this position.
Bring your left leg all the way back behind you again.
Place your hands on the front of your mat.
Tuck your left tail and then you're going to push back into the free leg of dog
that we've just been in.
Nice, we're just going to stay here for a moment.
What we can do is we can actually bend the right leg just to open the hips a
little bit more into this posture.
Nice and straighten the leg again before bringing it down into our downward dog
.
Perfect. We're going to repeat this on the other side.
So just take a nice deep breath in as we lift our left leg.
And as we exhale, bring the leg all the way forward into our pigeon pose on our
left side.
Again, just check your position name.
And when we're doing any knee bends, just make sure that you have your ankle
flexed.
So instead of like this, flexes like that because that protects the knee.
So if you've got your knee bent, always going to keep it flexed again.
Yeah, you're just protecting all of the ligaments and stuff in your knee.
So the front leg, the left leg, the ankle should be flexed, the knee should be
bent,
your back leg should be nice and straight.
And if you can, lower yourself forward onto the mat and allow your hair to rest
on the mat.
Remember to stay with the breath.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, now if you're ready, you can bring yourself back up, just take a slight
back bend again,
like we done with the last time.
And now we're going to bring our right leg all the way around in front of us,
all the way over to the other side.
Plant your foot on the floor, make sure both of your bone cheeks are on the
floor.
Bring your left arm over to your right knee and your right hand behind you.
Put your palm flat on the floor and take your gaze behind your right shoulder.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Release ourselves and just take ourselves over to the side with a quick onto
posture.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Perfect, nice, we can release ourselves from this posture, bring our right leg
all the way back.
Hook our right toe and push ourselves back into our three-length dog.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Again, we can bend this knee just to open off the hips a little bit more.
And then bring your strength again.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Or bring it down into the right arm with dog, while we're here we can take
child's ghost.
So we can just bring ourselves down to our knees, bring the knees nice and wide
,
bring the toes together, push your hips back, bring your head to the mat.
It's interesting for you to do breaths here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now we're going to jump in walk-off feet all the way forward to the front of
our mat.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So while we're in this forward fold, grab both your elbows, gently rock side to
side.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Feel a nice stretch on the back of your legs.
Remember to breathe like some big leaguer.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's inhale and bring ourselves back up to standing.
Stretch our arms over our head like before.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And exhale to bring your hands to a hard centre.
Okay, nice.
How is everyone going?
How is this pace for you all as am I going too slow or too fast?
Or is it going okay?
Or good?
>> That's good.
>> Perfect, okay.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay now, let's head back into mountain pose on the front of our mat.
Now we're going to go into Warrior II.
So Warrior II looks like this.
You're going to step your right foot back.
So your front foot is facing forward and the back foot is facing to the side.
And it's in line with each other.
And then we're going to bring our arms up.
Make sure they're in line and bend into our front knee for Warrior II.
We really want to focus on talking the tailbones.
We don't want to be sticking our bombs out over the sides.
We want to talk it in to really open up the hips.
We want to keep our shoulders down and open up our heart space as well here.
And just look to your front hand.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Two more breaths in this posture.
And while the next breath, we're going to straighten our front knee.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And we're going to take ourselves into triangle pose.
So we're basically just going to tilt forward.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So there's a few variations you can have your hand on your leg here.
Or you can bring your hand all the way down to the mat, whatever suits you
today.
And we're going to take our gaze up to our right hand.
And again, remember just to keep the shoulders away from the ears.
Keep your body nice and long.
And just breathe.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Everywhere ready, we can retain ourselves back.
And step to the front of your mat, back to the mountain pose.
Perfect.
Okay, we're going to repeat this on the other side.
So step your left leg back.
Bring your arms off, make sure they're nice and in line.
And then bend into your front knee.
And take your gaze to your front hand.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
One more breath here.
Now we're going to push back to straighten both of our legs.
And bend to the side to take triangle pose.
Take your gaze up to your left hand.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Nice, on the next exhale, you can release yourself from the posture.
Bring yourself back to mountain pose.
Perfect, okay. Now we're going to head into goddess pose.
So goddess pose, you can step even left for back.
It doesn't matter.
We're going to turn off the slightly outward.
So then I'll face them completely forward with a bit of a bend.
Oh yeah, perfect.
You know Sarah, bend legs and bring your arms like this.
Amazing.
This is goddess pose. There's nice opening of our hips and our groin and also
our heart space as well.
Good strength in all your legs as well.
I train legs to die so my legs are bent a little bit right now.
Let's take two more deep breaths.
On the next exhale, bring yourself back to standing.
Perfect. Okay, so while our legs are out like this,
we can just bring our feet facing forward now again.
Put the toes a little bit more square.
We're going to go for a forward felt here.
Gonna breathe in as we bring our hands above our head.
And exhale as we fold all the way forward.
And place your hands on the mat.
And if it's in your practice today, you can bring your hands up in the air
above your head
and interlace your fingers
and pull your hands forward over your head.
Make sure that it's free deeply into this posture.
Your hands are interlaced, you can undo them now.
And we're going to just do some twists.
So we're going to walk our hands over to the right side over to your right leg.
Gonna hold your right leg with your left hand.
You'll possibly be able to do that if not,
you can just place it on the mat as close to it as you can.
And then you can lift your right arm above your head.
Right back.
Really push into the twist.
If you want to, you can bring the arm as in the air all the way over to your
left thigh
for even more of a twist.
Perfect.
Hi, let's release this side.
Take ourselves over to the other side.
Gently walk your hands over, grab your ankle or the mat.
Bring your hands above your head.
And then we're going to squeeze yourself back to centre.
And on the next inhale, bring yourself up to a standing position.
Bring in your arms with your head.
Now on exhale, bring your arms to heart centre.
Perfect.
Okay, we can take ourselves back to the front of our mat again.
I'd like to say as well, if at any moment the practice has become a bit too
much,
you can just take yourself into child's pose.
And just relax, come back to the breath and then return to the class whenever
you're ready.
So now we're going to do tree pose.
So for tree pose, it's one that's going to require some balance.
So maybe just try to find a spot in your room that you can focus on.
That'll help with your balance.
Let's shift all of our weight to our right leg.
Lift our left leg.
Now it's up to you where you want to place it.
If you're not feeling so balanced today, you can place at the bottom of your
leg here.
That's no problem.
If you feel as though you've got good balance today, you can bring it up in
your thigh.
Perfect.
Let's start with our hands at heart centre.
Take some deep breaths.
And if you're able to, you can slowly bring your hands above your head.
Even more of a stretch.
Just as has your balance a little bit more.
Perfect girls.
Let's stay here for three breaths.
So on the next exhale, just release your hands down.
And release the leg.
With control.
Nice.
Let's do the other side.
Let's shift our weight to our left side.
Bring the right leg up.
Hands to heart centre.
Focus on one part of the room.
And if you're able to bring your hands all the way up.
Keep in the breath nice and deep and long.
One more breath, and then we can release on the exhale.
With control.
Nice.
Now we're going to bring ourselves to about a third
of the way in a normal.
So not all the way in the middle, but about here.
When I bring our hands to heart centre again and go on our tiptoes all the way.
Then on the exhale, we're slowly lower ourselves down while staying on our tipt
oes.
So just bring yourself all the way down, nice and slow.
And then when we get down here, we're going to start here for a couple of
breaths.
Nice.
Keep it back nice and straight.
Push the altars down.
One more breath.
And on the exhale, you can bring your knees forward onto your mat.
Yep, perfect.
Just going to give a nice opening, a lot of feet here.
So now we're going to bring our hands into a prayer position behind our back or
just hold each
each elbow like this.
I'll show you that we're even going to do this to just open up the chest.
Or we're going to bring our hands into prayer position like this.
Whatever is in your practice today.
I'm just going to stay here for five breaths and just really feel your heart
space opening
with this posture.
And you find it gets too much on your feet.
You can release your toes, no problem.
Do what your body needs.
A final breath.
And on the exhale, we release as usual.
So on the exhale, you can bring your toes left, like on top of your toes.
Bring your bone to your toes, like your feet like this.
Perfect.
And on off your hands.
Great.
Okay.
Now we're just going to stretch out our neck a little bit.
So we can take our right hand and place it on the side of our head, keeping our
head straight,
looking forward and our left hand down to the side just to elongate this part
even more to
create more of a stretch and pull your head to the right side.
Keeping your body straight, keeping everything straight over there in your neck
.
Feel a nice stretch along the left side of your neck.
Hope to be very gentle with this.
One more breath.
And release on the exhale.
Let's do the other side.
We release on the exhale.
Right, go over to the other side again.
But this time we're going to push on close up.
This time we're just going to get our hands and push this way.
So instead of tanning that way, you're tanning like that.
So push that side and have this arm out as well.
So you can just really create length here.
Yeah, perfect girls.
Feel a lovely stretch down the left side of your neck and your shoulder.
And let's do the other side.
Make momentum breathe nice and deeply.
Head back we can release and come back to the centre.
Now we're going to take our hands into preposition and push our
and under our chin and push our head back.
Again, just be gentle and go at your own pace.
One more breath.
Release on the exhale.
Right, now we're going to interlace our fingers.
Put our hands on the back of our head and push our head down just to stretch
out the back of our neck.
Keep in the back nice and straight.
Feel all of the tension just melt away.
Next exhale back to the centre.
In back to centre on the next exhale.
Perfect.
Now we're going to do some head rotation.
So just think, keep your body nice and straight and with the breath,
just rotate your head all the way around nice and gently and nice and slow.
Got your own pace here.
Let's do the other side.
Take it in the other direction.
We're going to turn back to neutral.
Let's see if there was a message in the chat, we're just going to see what we
said.
My body is clinging so much, I'll bless you.
Okay, so let's do some cut cows.
So we're going to inhale on the cow so cow looks like this.
So we're going to come to a tabletop position with our
hands directly under our shoulders and our knees directly under our hips.
And we're going to inhale as we look up and stick our bum out.
We'll cut really off just fine and exhale as we round all the way up into cut.
Inhale
and exhale.
Exhale
really push through
back in, back out.
Exhale
Let's do two more inhale.
Exhale, that's one.
Inhale
and exhale.
Okay, nice, I can turn to neutral.
So now we're just going to do, well we're here, just some body rolls
and I want you to do this at your own pace and with your own breath.
And there's no right or wrong way of doing this.
I just like to do this because it makes me just really open up my hips and my
body.
So I'm just going to just roll on anyway my body wants to.
You can go side to side like a snake keeping like your head around whatever
your body needs just to
open up and let the energy flow.
So you can go side to side like a snake.
Do whatever your body needs right now.
I'm going to turn to neutral and our table top position and now we're going to
thread the needle.
So we're going to make sure all in line again as we was before nice and square,
nice and straight.
And now we're going to bring our right arm up in the air, look to our right arm
.
Then as we exhale we want to thread the needle.
And bring our right shoulder to the mat.
Just sit here for a moment, find your breath.
Move on the next back.
So we can release your left table top position.
Perfect.
On the next inhale, reach your left arm of your head
and exhale as you thread the needle on the other side.
So we're going to bring our right side to side like a snake.
So we're going to turn the needle on the other side and exhale as you thread
the needle.
So that's going to make sure you thread the needle on the other side of your
head.
So we're going to be putting the needle on the other side.
So we're going to be putting the needle on the other side and exhale as you
thread the needle.
So we're going to be putting the needle on the other side.
So we're going to be putting the needle on the other side and exhale as you
thread the needle.
thread the needle on the other side.
So we're going to be putting the needle on the other side and exhale as you
thread the needle.
So we're going to be putting the needle on the other side.
Okay, so while we're here, we're going to do some flunks.
So we can start in a high plank like this.
Or if that's not in your practice, you can come to a low plank on your elbows.
And if it's in your practice today, we can do 10 reach out.
So opposite hands and opposite foot.
If not, just stay in your plank.
Nice. Bring ourselves a child's pose for the moment just to find our breath.
And when we're ready, let's push back to our final downward dog of the practice
.
Find length in your spine here.
You can pedal feet out or keep them still wherever you prefer.
But let's stay here for five breaths.
And on the next exhale, we can jump ourselves into a seated position or just
walk our feet forward and sit, sit down.
Okay, perfect.
Come into the end of our practice now.
And I just wanted to ask if there were any postures that were not in today's
practice that you would like me to add in.
Anything that you're really feeling that your body needs today that we haven't
covered?
No? All good? What about you, Laura? Would you say something?
No, sorry. I can't hear you properly, so I was just putting it by my ear.
Oh, sorry. Is it me? Am I too quiet?
I've got to just try calling you. I was in the middle of doing this.
So it's just glad with the volume for some reason.
Oh, okay. Sorry.
But maybe because I'm so far away, it's been hard to hear me.
Now it's a few more questions now, and then we're going to finish off.
So while we're on our seated position, we can just sit ourselves on our bum.
And we're going to gently lower ourselves to the back of our mat.
So just very, very, very, very, very low yourself down to a lying down position
.
And while we're here, we're going to take happy baby.
So you're going to bend the knees and bring them up to your chest.
You can either hold your knees, you can hold your ankles, your feet or your
toes.
So the yogi grip is to have two fingers out like this and hook them around your
big toes.
If that's not in your practice, just hold your knees. No problem.
We're just going to gently rock from side to side.
Just do whatever your body needs in this moment.
And stretch your legs forward, you can stretch them to the side, whatever you
want.
I just like to wing it on this one.
To really stretch out my legs.
Bring your legs together and rock yourself up into a seated position.
Now we're going to do both pose. So another one that's going to work our core.
So we're just going to come onto a seated position, bring our legs up
and bring our arms straight forward, if we can.
And if you can, stretch your legs all the way up.
Or we'll just keep them bent whatever is in your practice.
Perfect.
Nice, girls.
Perfect the back nice and straight. Nice.
Let's stay here for the 10 breaths.
That's really challenge ourselves today.
Keep the breath nice and long and we're halfway.
Two more breaths.
And then the last breath, lower yourself back to the floor slowly like you did
earlier,
vertebrae by vertebrae, even the core gauge.
Nice.
Okay, we're going to do a universal spinal twist now.
So I'm going to bring your right leg up, bend up the knee.
Grab your right knee with your left hand.
Bring your right knee over to the left side.
Extend the right arm all the way out to the side, nice and straight.
And take your gaze over to the right.
Be a nice twist in the spine here.
Try to keep the right shoulder on the mat.
Nice, on the exhale, let's release.
And let's do the other side.
Bring the right left leg up.
All over to the right and take your gaze to the left.
Keep the left shoulder on the mat.
[silence]
And it's left, release or self on this posture.
Now we're going to prepare ourselves for shavasana.
So we're going to bring our legs, both our legs up.
Squeeze really tight into the chest where you give yourself a nice big tight
bottle.
[silence]
You can rock side to side.
And we'll take a nice big inhale and squeeze really hard.
And then on the exhale, let it all go and lie out in a flat position on the mat
.
In core pose, shavasana.
And now that you're here, gently close down the eyes.
So shavasana is used for relaxation at the end of the practice.
So take this time
to lie down on your mat to get really comfortable.
Take any micro movements that you need to do now,
just to make yourself extra comfortable for your shavasana.
So you can just lie down on your mat in core pose.
I'm not going to do this with you.
Or what?
So you can take this moment to think about your intention for today's practice.
Take some nice deep breaths and allow your nervous system to completely relax.
Focus on the rhythm of your breath.
You can take this moment to find gratitude for yourself and for your body
and for turning up to this practice today.
Take some nice deep breaths and allow the body to sink deeply into the air
beneath you.
Your body is safe, grounded and supported.
Allow this moment to release any tension that your body might be holding.
And allow your breath to deepen and become even more relaxed.
If your mind wonders, that's okay, but you can gently bring your attention back
to the breath.
Allow all of your muscles to relax, letting go of any tension.
Just imagine your body sinking deeper and deeper into the air beneath you.
Soften your whole body.
Allow all of your muscles to relax.
And remember that you're not needed anywhere right now over then right here.
Allow this time for yourself.
Stay with the breath. Keep the focus on your breath.
You can also feel the focus on your body.
We all have such busy lives but we can remember to always come back to this
peace and calm whenever we need to.
Now I'd like you to gently start bringing awareness back to the body.
Keep in the eyes closed whenever you're ready. Start to gently move your
fingers
and your toes. You might want to stretch your arms all the way above for a nice
long stretch.
Keep in the eyes closed. Roll yourself over onto your right side,
laying down on your right side with your eyes closed.
And even though we know we're about to get up and go on with our day,
just allow yourself a few more moments of this peace and calm.
Allow yourself to feel completely relaxed.
And whenever you're ready, keeping the eyes closed, bring yourself to a
comfortable
seated position just like we did at the start of the practice.
However that looks for you right now.
Let's place our hands on our lap with our palms facing upwards for receiving.
And we're going to chant free arms together.
The first arm is for ourself and our own inner peace and freedom.
The second is for those around us and the third is a universal wish for love,
freedom and peace.
We're going to inhale and exhale with an arm.
Bring our hearts to hand centre and not our head.
To bow to the practice.
Namaste.
Oh, is that girls? You did great.
I enjoyed it.
Yeah, so did she.
Nice. You're done.
Oh, good. I'm glad.
Just what it needs.
Love that. Well, thank you for coming. You've both done so well.
And thank you, thank you.
The guys, just through that practice.
I feel all nice and nimble now.
Amazing. I just feel relaxed and ready for bed.
Oh, that's not good. Have you got much on today or are you able to relax?
Yeah, no, I've got to go to work.
Hopefully soon you'll come after this relaxation and you'll feel full power.
Feel revitalized.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, I'll go for a walk in the sunshine now.
Oh, nice. Is it really sunny back home at the moment?
Yeah, yeah, it's quite sunny here. It's lovely.
Nice.
No worries.
Well, let's go these days tomorrow so we need to go to town.
I don't need to go to gym, so that's it, really.
Lovely. Nice.
Okay, then. Well, enjoy your day, girls.
And thank you.
I'm going to use both really great and it was a pleasure to host this class.
So thank you so, so much.
And thank you.
Is it a bad time for you, no, Georgia?
It's just gone 7pm, so not quite bedtime, but yeah, it's getting to the evening
now.
Yeah, that's crazy.
We're just starting our day and like, it's night time where you are.
It is, isn't it?
It's much.
And it's even closer in time now.
It used to be a few months ago.
Would it be 9pm now for me?
Because now the clocks both changed both ends.
Oh, that's crazy.
Yeah, so it's even like two months ago.
It would have been even a longer stretch out, if that makes sense.
But yeah, it's it's in.
Yeah, what?